Edward A. Kane 008
People's Archive, MLK Library
Edward A. Kane Papers
1953-1979
People's Archive, MLK Library
Kane, Edward A.
008
2 Boxes
1.75 Linear feet
Arrangement
Federation of Citizens Associations Michigan Park Citizens Association National Gateway Citizens' Association Northeast Council of Citizens' Association Woodridge-Michigan Park News Photograph
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Edward A. Kane (1902-1998) was born in Massachusetts and arrived in D.C. in 1924. Kane attended the University of Massachusetts, earned a Masters in chemistry from Catholic University, and a doctorate in biochemistry from Georgetown University. Kane worked for the Department of Agriculture in the Agriculture Research Service for 38 years, retiring in 1965. Kane served in the Army Air Corps during World War II; and then in the Air Force Reserves, retiring as a colonel in 1965.
Mary (Kerwin) Kane (1907-1993) was born in Silver Lake, Wisconsin and arrived in D.C. in 1923. She attended George Washington University and was a secretary for Representative Hamer Harold Budge (R-Idaho), Senator Frank J. Lausche (D-Ohio), and Senator/Vice President Walter Mondale (D- Minn.. She retired in 1979.
The Kane's were married in 1935 and had three children. They were active members of the Health Committee of the Federation of Citizens Association, the Michigan Park Citizens Association, the National Gateway Citizens' Association, and the Northeast Council of Citizens' Association. Dr. Kane served as Chairman of the Health Committee and Mrs. Kane served as President of the Michigan Park Citizens Association and the Northeast Council of Citizens Associations. In 1968 Dr. Kane was the recipient of the Washington Star award from the Federation of Citizens Associations for his community work.
Custodial History
Donated by Dr. Edward A. Kane and Mrs. Mary Kane in 1988.
Scope and Contents
The papers include correspondence, meeting minutes, newsletters, reports, resolutions, and membership lists from the Federation of Citizens Associations, the Michigan Park Citizens Association, the National Gateway Citizens' Association, and the Northeast Council of Citizens' Association. The papers also contain newspaper clippings and a photograph of Dr. Kane as a young man. The collection is arranged by Association or Organization name.
Neighborhoods; Citizens' Associations; Organizational Records; Minutes (Records); Newsletters; Correspondence; Michigan Park (Washington, D.C.)
- Federation of Citizens Association, 1950-1989; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Box 1)
  - Newsletter, 1980-1983; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 1)
  - Federation of Citizens Association, Health Committee, 1950-1989; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 2)
- Michigan Park Citizens Association, 1955-1985; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Box 1)
  - Constitution, undated, 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 3)
  - Membership list, 1981-1982; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 4)
  - Meeting minutes, 1980-1982; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1980-1985; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 6)
  - General, 1955-1985; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 7)
- National Gateway Citizens' Association, 1955; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Box 1)
  - National Gateway Citizens' Association, 1955; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 8)
- Northeast Council of Citizens' Association, 1955-1966; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Box 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1956; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1956; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1955-1956; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 2)
  - Newsletter, 1955; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1950-1960; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 4)
  - General, 1953-1966; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 5)
- Michigan Park Citizens Association, 1961; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Box 2)
  - Woodridge-Michigan Park News, 1961; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 6)
- Photograph, 1958; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Box 2)
  - Dr. Edward A. Kane, 1958-04-16; 1.75 Linear feet 2 boxes (Folder 7)